A Finding Aid to the Yasuo Kuniyoshi Papers, 1906-2013, in the Archives of American Art AAA.kuniyasu
Archives of American Art
Yasuo Kuniyoshi papers
1906-2013
AAA.kuniyasu
Archives of American Art
11.8 Linear feet
The papers of artist Yasuo Kuniyoshi measure 11.8 linear feet and date from 1906-2013. The collection documents his career as a painter, graphic artist, and photographer, as well as his involvement in political, social, and art organizations, especially during World War II. Included are biographical material; correspondence; writings by Kuniyoshi and others; subject files primarily on his participation in various organizations and business dealings with American and Japanese galleries, museums, and dealers; exhibition catalogs and other printed material; photographs of Kuniyoshi and others; and artwork; exhibition and artwork records; and four scrapbooks. The collection also contains materials on Kuniyoshi's career and artwork obtained after his death by his widow Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi.
Kuniyoshi, Yasuo
Provenance
The collection was donated in installments, from 1969 to 1995, by Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi, Yasuo Kuniyoshi's widow. Additional papers were donated in 2014 by Stephen Diamond, Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi's nephew.
Restrictions on Access
A portion of the collection has been digitized. Use of material not digitized requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Alternative Forms Available
A portion of the papers of Yasuo Kuniyoshi were digitized in 2005 by the Archives of American Art, and total 1852 images.
Related Archival Materials note
Also found at the Archives of American Art are the Yasuo Kuniyoshi photographs of artwork, a 1948 letter from Kuniyoshi to E. P. Richardson, and checklists of Yasuo Kuniyoshi prints.
Biographical Note
Yasuo Kuniyoshi (1889-1953) was a Japanese-American painter, printmaker and photographer in New York, N.Y.
Kuniyoshi was born in Okayama, Japan. In 1906 he came to the United States and a year later began studying at the Los Angeles School of Art and Design. In 1910 he moved to New York and took courses at the National Academy of Design, the Independent School of Art, and the Art Students League, where he studied with Kenneth Hayes Miller. He was married to fellow artist Katherine Schmidt from 1919 to 1932. After traveling throughout Europe, they moved to the Woodstock, New York, in 1927 and took part in the Woodstock Art Colony. Kuniyoshi studied and later taught at the Art Students League summer school there. By 1930 he had established himself as an internationally known painter and graphic artist. In New York City he taught at the Art Students League, the New School for Social Research, and served as the first president of the Artists Equity Association from 1947 to 1950. Kuniyoshi was active in social organizations, especially Japanese American organizations, such as the Japanese American Committee for Democracy, and took an active role in the war effort during World War II. Yasuo Kuniyoshi died in 1953 and was survived by his second wife Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi who preserved the legacy of his work.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of artist Yasuo Kuniyoshi measure 11.8 linear feet and date from 1906-2013. The collection documents his career as a painter, graphic artist, and photographer, as well as his involvement in political, social, and art organizations, especially during World War II. Included are biographical material; correspondence; writings by Kuniyoshi and others; subject files primarily on his participation in various organizations and business dealings with American and Japanese galleries, museums, and dealers; exhibition catalogs and other printed material; photographs of Kuniyoshi and others; and artwork; exhibition and artwork records; and four scrapbooks. The collection also contains materials on Kuniyoshi's career and artwork obtained after his death by his widow Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged as 10 series. Additions to the collection received in 2014 were integrated in the finding aid according to appropriate series, but not physically integrated. Thus, box numbers may be out of order.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1906-1990s (Boxes 1, 5; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1931-2004 (Boxes 1, 5-6; 1.2 linear feet)
Series 3: Writings, 1939-2000 (Boxes 1, 6; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 4: Subject Files, circa 1920s-2009 (Boxes 1-2, 6-8; 2.9 linear feet)
Series 5: Printed Material, 1921-2013 (Boxes 2-3, 8, 16; 1.5 linear feet)
Series 6: Photographs, circa 1920s-2001 (Boxes 3, 9, 15; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 7: Artwork, 1927-circa 1940s (Boxes 3, 9, OV 4; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 8: Exhibition Files, 1953-2004 (Boxes 9-10; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 9: Artwork Records, circa 1920s-2004 (Boxes 10-13, 16, 18; 3.3 linear feet)
Series 10: Scrapbooks, 1919-1978 (Boxes 13-14, 17; 0.6 linear feet)
Art, Modern--20th century; Asian American artists; Japanese American art; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Photographers--New York (State)--New York; Photographs; Political clubs; Printmakers--New York (State)--New York; Scrapbooks; World War, 1939-1945--Japanese Americans
- Biographical Material, 1906-1990s; Series 1; 0.2 Linear feet Boxes 1, 5
  Scope and Contents note
  Found here are biographical summaries and resumes, as well as vital records, documentation regarding Kuniyoshi's death, an address book, and records of the painting materials an formulas that he used. Also of note are his citizenship applications, travel records, and indentification documents regarding his status as a citizen of a foreign nation.
  Existence and Location of Copies note
  One folder has been scanned.
  - Biographical Material, 1948, 1951, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Summaries, 1934-circa 1950s; 1990s (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Information Compiled by Hirshhorn Museum, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Address Book, circa 1930s (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cemetery Records, 1964; 1954 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Citizenship Application, 1946-1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Estate Tax, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Identification Records, 1906-1953 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Letterhead and Copy of Signature, circa 1950s; undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Marriage Records, 1933-circa 1935 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Memorial Guest Register and Condolence Cards, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Obituaries, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Painting Formulas and Materials, circa 1940s-1990s (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Travel Permits, 1942-1945 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1931-2004; Series 2; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 1, 5-6
  Arrangement note
  Correspondence which was part of the original gift to the Archives of American Art are arranged first, followed Yasuo and Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi correspondence which was donated in 2014 and is arranged alphabetically.
  The small amount of Yasuo Kuniyoshi correspondence discusses various topics including exhibits and his status as a Japanese American during World War II. Additionally there are letters sent to Kuniyoshi by Sheldon School students about his career as an artist and his letters in reply, and letters of recommendation he compiled to vouch for his character and work as an artist, in case he needed them during his 1941 travels around the United States.
  Also found is correspondence to Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi after Yasuo's death including letters of condolence and letters requesting the inclusion of his work in exhibits and publications. Of note is her correspondence with Karl Fortess, Alexander Brook, Tom Wolf, and the Yasuo Kuniyoshi Museum in Japan. Researchers should note that additional correspondence relating to certain subjects may be found in Series 4: Subject Files.
  This series has been partially scanned.
  - General Correspondence, 1941-1962, 1971-1989 undated (Box 1, Folder 2-6)
  - Correspondence with Sheldon School Students, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence between Yasuo and Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi, 1951; circa 1941 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Letters of Recommendation for Travel in US, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Yasuo Kuniyoshi, Alphabetical Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Artists for Victory, 1942-1944 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - A-F, 1939-1954 (Box 5, Folder 17-19)
    - Greenbaum, Edward S., 1943-1950; 1931 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - G-N, 1939-1952 (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
    - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, 1942-1950 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - P-Z, 1939-1952 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi, Alphabetical Correspondence
    - A, 1990s; circa 1952-1970 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Brook, Alexander, 1973; circa 1953 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - B-C, 1954-2003 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Davis-Serisawa, Marsha, 1968-2000 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Diamond Family, 1991-2004 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Dorfman, Bruce, 1992-2000 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - D-E, 1953-2002 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Fortess, Karl, 1953-1971 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Friends of Art at Colby College, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Fujikawa, Fujie, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - F-G, 1954-2002 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Gallery Olym, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - H, 1954-2004 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Iwamoto, Ralph, circa 1987 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - J, 1953-1999 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Kanemitsu, Matsumi "Mike", 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - K-L, 1954-1999 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Matsumoto, Fumihisa, 1998-2001 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1953-2002 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - M, 1953-2001 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Nakada, Yoshie, 1950-1968 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - National Museum of American Art, 1987; 1985 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - New York Artists Equity Association, 1992-1999 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - N, 1954-2004 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Okada, Masumi, circa 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Okayama Prefectural Museum of Art (Katsumi Senoo), 1988-1996 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Ozawa, Hidetoshi (Yamatane Corporation), circa 1985-2003 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Ozawa, Ritsuko (Yasuo Kuniyoshi Museum), 1993-2001 (Box 5, Folder 53-55)
    - Ozawa, Yoshio, 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - O, 1977-1998 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Prescott, Emma-Stina, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Prince, David, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - P-R, 1953-1998 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Seckel, Cornelia, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Secunda, Arthur, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Serisawa, Mary, 1966-2002 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Sternberg, Harry, circa 1974 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Sugihara, Sumi, circa 1954-1968 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - S, 1953-2004 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Tagawa, Toyoko, circa 1980-1993 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Takashige, Anne, 1990-2003 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Tokyo Shimbun, 1975-1982 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - T-V, 1953-1999 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Wolf, Tom, circa 1987-2003 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - W-Y, 1953-2003 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Yamazaki-Kleps, Akiko, circa 1996-2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified and First Names Only, circa 1983-2003 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Writings, 1939-2000; Series 3; 0.4 Linear feet Boxes 1, 6
  Writings which were part of the original gift to the Archives of American Art are arranged first, followed by a second list of the files donated in 2014.
  Writings include Kuniyoshi's writings and speeches about other artists, art and the art profession, lithography, and World War II. Also found are statements on his own work and extensive notes for his autobiography. Writings by others about Kuniyoshi include essays by Tom Wolf, Elsie McIlroy, John Baur, and Lloyd Goodrich. Additionally there are many notes on Kuniyoshi and his artwork written by Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi.
  - About Other Artists, 1942, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Art and the Art Profession, 1940-1952, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Artist Statements, 1944, 1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Civilization Besieged: The Artist's Role in War", undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "East to West", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lithography, 1946, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Notes for Autobiography, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Preliminary Notes for Autobiography, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Writings by Others About Kuniyoshi, 1948, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "American Art", circa 1940 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "Creative Process", undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "Drawings", 1946 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Writings by Kuniyoshi, circa 1940s (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Notes by Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi, circa 1950s-2000 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Writings by Tom Wolf, circa 1990s (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Thesis, "Yasuo Kuniyoshi, A Japanese-American Artist and the Second World War" by Midori Yoshimoto, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "Kuniyoshi's America and the War Against Japan" by Gene Thornton, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "Yasuo Kuniyoshi" by Julian E. Levi, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Subject Files, circa 1920s-2009; Series 4; 2.9 Linear feet Boxes 1-2, 6-8
  Found here are files on various aspects of Kuniyoshi's career which document his involvement in social, political, and art organizations, including the East West Association, the Artists Equity Association, and the Japanese American Committee for Democracy. These records include correspondence, speeches, printed material and other notes. Also found are transcripts of the radio broadcast, "Japan Against Japan," a few exhibition records, card file inventories of Kuniyoshi's work owned by the Metropolitan Museum of Art, and records of his participation in the Woodstock Art Conference.
  Many of the files found here were created by Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi during the management of the exhibition and sale of artwork after Kuniyoshi's death. Included are gallery records, especialy documenting Kuniyoshi's dealings with the Downtown Gallery and Zabriskie Galleries; files regarding art dealers and collectors in both the United States and Japan; and other records of gifts, publication, sales, and special projects.
  Subject files which were part of the original gift to the Archives of American Art are arranged alphabetically first, followed by a second alphabetical list of the files donated in 2014. Researchers should note that there are a few subjects which have files in both lists.
  - An American Group, Inc., 1939-1951, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Artists' Equity Association, 1946-1952, undated (Box 1, Folder 18-21)
  - Arts Council of Japanese Americans for Democracy, 1942-1944, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Card File Inventory of Etchings, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dallas Art Association, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Declaration of Loyalty, Committee of Japanese Artists Resident in New York City, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - East and West Association, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Greater New York Committee For Japanese Americans, Inc., 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Japanese American Anthology Collection, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Japanese American Committee for Democracy, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Kuniyoshi Memorial Exhibition, Japan, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - List of Gifts to Kuniyoshi Museum, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Mainichi Press International Exhibition, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1948-1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Museum of Modern Art Card File Inventory, undated (Box 1, Folder 34-36)
  - Office of War Information Poster Project, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Radio Broadcast, "Japan Against Japan", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Retrospective Exhibition, Whitney Museum of Art, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture Lecture, Transcript, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture Lecture, 7" Reel-to-Reel Audio Tapes, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 41-42)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture Lecture, Duplicate Cassette Tape, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - United China Relief, Inc., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - United Nations In America Dinner, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Woodstock Art Conference, 1947-1952, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - An American Group, Inc., 1942-1945 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Artists Equity Association, 1949-2002 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Authentication of Artwork, 1973-2007 (Box 6, Folder 16-20)
  - Benesse Collection, 1991-2002 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1931-1951 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Conner-Rosencranz, 1991-2004 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Crane Kallman Gallery, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Downtown Gallery, Artwork Labels, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Downtown Gallery, Consignments and Sales, 1939-1969 (Box 6, Folder 26-35)
  - Downtown Gallery, Estate Records, 1953-1973; 1986 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Downtown Gallery, Gallery Closure and Auction, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Downtown Gallery, Inventory Lists, 1951; 1937-1949; 1969 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Downtown Gallery, Miscellaneous, 1939; 1943-1955 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Downtown Gallery, Notebook of Sales, 1953-1979 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Franklin Riehlman (Allison Galleries), 1986-2003 (Box 6, Folder 41-42)
  - Franklin Riehlman (Allison Galleries), 1986-2003 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Fukutake Publishing, 1982-2001 (Box 7, Folder 2-5)
  - Gallery Nii, Osaka, Inventory Records, circa 2000 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Gifts to Archives of American Art, circa 1989-1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Gift to Japanese American National Museum, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Gifts of Artwork to Museum of Modern Art, 1953-1990 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Gifts of Artwork to New York Artists Equity Association, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Gifts to Yasuo Kuniyoshi Museum, 1993-2000 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Gifts of Artwork to Institutions, 1953-2002 (Box 7, Folder 12-15)
  - Howard Greenberg Gallery, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Japanese Artists Association, 1950-1952 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Jules Pascin Painting Valuation, 1958-1996 (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
  - Kuniyoshi Memorial Exhibition, Japan, 1953-1956 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Lists of Artwork, 1949-1973 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Lists of Collectors and Museum Directors, circa 1950s-1990s (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Mainichi Press International Exhibitions, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Natenshi Gallery, 1973-1988 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Office of War Information Poster Project, 1940s; 1996 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Painting of Train Owned by Kuniyoshi, 1980s; circa 1920s (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Paul Galleries, Inc. (Paul Watabe), 1968-1978 (Box 7, Folder 28-30)
  - Reproduction Requests, 1969; 1988-1998 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Requests from Japanese Publications, 1974-1995 (Box 7, Folder 32-33)
  - Requests from Japanese Television Productions, 1975-1985 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Salander-O'Reilly Galleries, Inc., circa 1981-1995 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Sales of Photographs, circa 1982-2000 (Box 7, Folder 36-37)
  - Slide Lists and Requests, circa 1950-1970s (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Toho Art Corporation, 1979-1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Tokyo Gallery, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Treasury Department War Bond Campaign, 1942-1945 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - VAGA Rights Administration, 1999; 2003; 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - William Pinckard Fine Prints, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Woodstock Art Conference, 1947; 1950 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Woodstock Artists Association, 1986-2003 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Yasuo Kuniyoshi Fund, Inc., 1953-2001 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Zabriskie Gallery, 1978-2003; 2009 (Box 8, Folder 9-15)
  - Zauho Press, 1974-1981 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Printed Material, 1921-2013; Series 5; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 2-3, 8, 16
  Found here are books, newspaper, and magazine clippings about Kuniyoshi and about World War II; exhibition catalogs and announcements; magazines; and miscellaneous event announcements, brochures, and bulletins. Researchers should note that additional printed material can be found within Series 10: Scrapbooks.
  Printed material which was part of the original gift to the Archives of American Art are arranged first, followed by a second list of the files donated in 2014.
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1940-1964, 1982, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, World War II, 1944-1945, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1936-1986 (Box 2, Folder 4-14)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Photocopies, 1921-1952 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  - Magazines, Art News, 1939, 1942, 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Magazines, Miscellaneous, 1924-1939 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - Magazines, Miscellaneous, 1940-1965, 1971 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 1-2)
  - Magazines, Miscellaneous, Photocopies, 1930-1949 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1934-1975 (Box 3 (hol), Folder 4)
  - Auction Catalogs, 1934-1985 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Book, Yasuo Kuniyoshi, American Artists Group Monograph, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Book, Yasuo Kuniyoshi by Lloyd Goodrich, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Book, Yasuo Kuniyoshi by William Murrell, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1924-2001 (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
  - Conference Report, "The Artist and the Museum", 1950 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1930s-2013 (Box 8, Folder 24-31)
  - Magazines and Newsletters, 1940; 1939; 1993; 1931 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Museum and Gallery Publications, circa 1990s (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Publications Regarding Copyright, circa 1950s; 1988 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1940s-2001 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Japanese Portfolio of Artwork Reproductions, 1932 (Box 16)
- Photographs, circa 1920s-2001; Series 6; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 3, 9, 15; (Box 3; 1 folder)
  Found here are photographs of Kuniyoshi in his studio, at various events and parties, teaching at Mills College and with his wife Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi. Numerous portraits of Kuniyoshi were taken by Konrad Cramer, Alfredo Valente, Peter A. Juley & Son, and others. Also found are photographs of artists, including Henry Mattson, Francis Criss, Julian Levi, Emil Ganso, Doris and Russell Lee, and others, taken by Yasuo Kuniyoshi. Of note are photographs of the Artists Equity Testimonial Dinner held in honor of Kuniyoshi's 1948 retrospective at the Whitney Museum of American Art. Researchers should note that photographs of artwork by Kuniyoshi can be found in Series 9: Artwork Records.
  - Artists Photographed by Kuniyoshi, 1936-1939, undated (Box 3 (hol), Folder 5)
  - Portraits of Yasuo Kuniyoshi, circa 1930s-1953 (Box 9, Folder 1-6)
    Oversized material housed in Box 15
  - Yasuo Kuniyoshi in His Studio, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
  - Snapshots of Yasuo Kuniyoshi, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Yasuo Kuniyoshi at Parties and Special Events, circa 1930s-1952 (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
  - Yasuo Kuniyoshi at Whitney Museum Dinner, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Yasuo Kuniyoshi with Others, circa 1920s-1950s (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Yasuo Kuniyoshi Teaching, circa 1949 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Yasuo Kuniyoshi Near Death, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Yasuo and Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi, circa 1940s (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Sara Mazo Kuniyoshi, circa 1998- 2001 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Dick Florsheim and Rico Lebrun, circa 1940s (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Unidentified Event, circa 1950 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Unidentified People in Costume, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Travel, Contact Sheets and Negatives, circa 1955-1958 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Paul Gallery Exhibition, circa 1973 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Exhibition Installations, 1931-circa 1940s (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Radio City Mural, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Artwork Depicting Kuniyoshi, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Artwork by Others, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Slides of Photography by Kuniyoshi, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Photographs of Kuniyoshi (Photocopies), undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Oversize Portraits of Yasuo Kuniyoshi from Box 9, Folders 1-6, circa 1930s-1950 (Box 15)
  - Oversize Photographs of Kuniyoshi at Parties and Special Events from Box 9, Folder 10-11, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 15)